Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[The Tower of Whispers]
[برج الهمسات]
[Episode 16]
[الحلقة 16]
Father, please investigate the truth
يا أبتي أرجوك أن تحقق في الحقيقة
and clear my name.
وأمسح اسمي.
Wait!
انتظر!
I don't think an investigation is necessary.
لا أعتقد أن هناك حاجة للتحقيق.
I have evidence of the crime right here.
لدي دليل على الجريمة هنا.
Who is this person?
من هو هذا الشخص؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
The Eldest Prince ordered a massacre at Xiaohe Village last night,
أمر الأمير الأكبر بمذبحة في قرية شياوهي الليلة الماضية،
leaving no survivors,
لم يترك أي ناجين،
so that auspicious clouds would appear in the sky
حتى تظهر السحب الميمونة في السماء
on the day of the ceremony.
في يوم الحفل.
But those were no auspicious clouds.
ولكن تلك لم تكن سحبًا ميمونة.
That was the fire from the destroyed Xiaohe Village.
كانت هذه النار من قرية شياوهي المدمرة.
This... this isn't true.
هذا...هذا ليس صحيحا.
Father,
أب،
I never did any of these things!
لم أفعل أيًا من هذه الأشياء أبدًا!
These are the confessions of your men after they were captured.
هذه اعترافات رجالكم بعد أن تم أسرهم.
What was destroyed today was just an empty village.
ما تم تدميره اليوم لم يكن سوى قرية فارغة.
The villagers of Xiaohe Village
قرويو قرية شياوهي
were evacuated by us beforehand.
لقد تم إخلائهم من قبلنا مسبقًا.
Your men have confessed
لقد اعترف رجالك
to all your evil deeds.
لجميع أعمالك الشريرة.
Take a good look for yourself.
أنظر جيدا لنفسك.
Who exactly deserves to die?
من يستحق الموت بالضبط؟
Well...
حسنًا...
Who are you?
من أنت؟
How dare you enter the palace uninvited?
كيف تجرؤ على دخول القصر دون دعوة؟
Guards!
حراس!
Father!
أب!
He called His Majesty Father.
فنادى جلالته بأبيه.
This...
هذا...
He's also a prince.
وهو أمير أيضاً.
Could it be...
هل يمكن أن يكون...
He's a prince?
هل هو أمير؟
Father, please calm your anger.
يا أبتي، أرجوك أن تهدأ من غضبك.
It's been a long time.
لقد مر وقت طويل.
Have you forgotten
هل نسيت؟
that you still have a son like me?
أن لديك ابنًا مثلي؟
It's you.
إنه أنت.
Jun Che?
جون تشي؟
Weren't you dead?
ألم تكن ميتا؟
I did die once,
لقد مت مرة واحدة
all thanks to you.
كل الشكر لك.
Now I've crawled back from hell
الآن زحفت عائدا من الجحيم
to claim your life.
للمطالبة بحياتك.
Jun Che,
جون تشي،
I'm glad that you're back.
أنا سعيد بعودتك.
Don't be foolish.
لا تكن أحمقا.
Let's wait until everything is investigated.
دعونا ننتظر حتى يتم التحقيق في كل شيء.
The evidence is irrefutable.
والدليل لا يقبل الجدل.
What's there to investigate?
ما الذي يجب التحقيق فيه؟
You just want to cover it up,
أنت فقط تريد تغطية الأمر،
to save the royal family's face
لإنقاذ ماء وجه العائلة المالكة
and bury the Eldest Prince's heinous crimes
ودفن الجرائم الشنيعة التي ارتكبها الأمير الأكبر
in darkness,
في الظلام،
keeping everyone in the dark.
إبقاء الجميع في الظلام.
This son you favor so much—
هذا الابن الذي تفضله كثيرًا
you think he's a capable and virtuous ruler,
تعتقد أنه حاكم قادر وفاضل،
but in fact,
ولكن في الواقع،
he's nothing but a complete fool,
إنه ليس سوى أحمق كامل،
a worthless coward without virtue or ability.
جبان لا قيمة له ولا فضيلة ولا قدرة.
You!
أنت!
I didn't come today
لم آتي اليوم
to discuss our father-son relationship.
لمناقشة علاقتنا كأب وابنه.
I'm here to tear away
أنا هنا للتمزيق
this hypocritical royal facade
هذه الواجهة الملكية المنافقة
and expose all the darkness within
وكشف كل الظلام في الداخل
to the light of day.
إلى ضوء النهار.
Let me see.
دعني أرى.
What is she doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
What is this?
ما هذا؟
[Lin's Clinic]
[عيادة لين]
Let me take a look.
دعني ألقي نظرة.
Now throughout the entire Daning City,
الآن في جميع أنحاء مدينة دانينج،
everyone has a copy of this manifesto.
كل شخص لديه نسخة من هذا البيان.
The crimes committed by the Eldest Prince
الجرائم التي ارتكبها الأمير الأكبر
are already known to all.
وهي معروفة بالفعل للجميع.
How could you possibly
كيف يمكنك ذلك؟
produce so many manifestos
إنتاج العديد من البيانات
in one single night?
في ليلة واحدة؟
[One day ago]
[منذ يوم واحد]
After decades of arduous study,
بعد عقود من الدراسة الشاقة،
you now find yourselves trapped here.
الآن تجدون أنفسكم محاصرين هنا.
I believe you must have questioned yourselves.
أعتقد أنكم يجب أن تتساءلوا عن أنفسكم.
Once you aspired to bring peace to the state,
لقد كنت تطمح ذات يوم إلى جلب السلام إلى الولاية،
but why are your writings now filled with nothing but flattery?
ولكن لماذا أصبحت كتاباتك الآن مليئة بالمجاملات فقط؟
Tonight,
الليلة،
I'd like to ask you all to pick up your brushes again,
أود أن أطلب منكم جميعًا أن تلتقطوا فرشاتكم مرة أخرى،
to write not praises but manifestos,
لا تكتب مديحًا بل بيانات،
denouncing the countless crimes of the Eldest Prince.
إدانة الجرائم العديدة التي ارتكبها الأمير الأكبر.
Whoever is willing to stand with me,
من يرغب في الوقوف معي،
raise your candle.
ارفع شمعتك.
These scholars all come from humble origins.
هؤلاء العلماء جميعهم ينحدرون من أصول متواضعة.
They studied hard to finally earn their titles.
لقد درسوا بجد حتى حصلوا في النهاية على ألقابهم.
They are children of common people,
إنهم أبناء عامة الناس،
and should become officials who serve those same common people.
ويجب أن يصبحوا مسؤولين يخدمون هؤلاء الناس العاديين.
[Lin's Clinic]
[عيادة لين]
But they were detained by the Eldest Prince
ولكن تم اعتقالهم من قبل الأمير الأكبر
and became ghostwriters for his achievements.
وأصبحوا كتابًا أشباحًا لإنجازاته.
Masterpieces written with human blood
روائع مكتوبة بالدم البشري
have hurt these scholars' feelings,
لقد جرحت مشاعر هؤلاء العلماء،
and will eventually damage Daning's national fortune.
وسوف يؤدي ذلك في نهاية المطاف إلى الإضرار بالثروة الوطنية لدانينج.
Right!
يمين!
All written by Daning scholars.
جميعها مكتوبة من قبل علماء دانينج.
Well said!
أحسنت القول!
Report!
تقرير!
Your Majesty,
جلالتك،
someone is spreading manifestos against the Eldest Prince in the city.
هناك شخص ينشر بيانات ضد الأمير الأكبر في المدينة.
The people are furious.
الناس غاضبون.
Even the Longxiang Guard can't hold them back.
حتى حرس لونغشيانغ لا يستطيعون إيقافهم.
What?
ماذا؟
This...
هذا...
Father,
أب،
you may want to protect him,
ربما تريد حمايته،
but the people won't allow it.
ولكن الشعب لن يسمح بذلك
Guards.
حراس.
Seize him!
إمسكوه!
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
-Your Majesty!
-جلالتك!
You harbinger of misfortune!
أنت نذير سوء الحظ!
How dare you prevent me from taking the throne!
كيف تجرؤ على منعي من أخذ العرش!
Today I will kill you!
سأقتلك اليوم!
This state will still be mine!
هذه الحالة ستظل ملكي!
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
This...
هذا...
Father,
أب،
my brother attempted assassination
لقد حاول أخي الاغتيال
and I've executed him on the spot.
وأعدمته على الفور.
Now
الآن
I am your only choice.
أنا خيارك الوحيد.
You!
أنت!
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Long live Your Majesty!
عاش جلالتك!
[Lu's Mansion]
[قصر لو]
His Majesty has arrived!
لقد وصل جلالته!
Cai Ping,
كاي بينغ,
where is the lady?
أين السيدة؟
My Lady says
تقول سيدتي
although she has forgiven you,
على الرغم من أنها سامحتك،
she's still upset
لا تزال مستاءة
and you have to show your sincerity.
وعليك أن تظهر صدقك.
My Lady,
سيدتي،
Five is here to apologize.
خمسة هنا للاعتذار.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
My Lady,
سيدتي،
I was wrong.
لقد كنت مخطئا.
♪ The night rain dropped on the front yard to witness separation in the world ♪
♪ هطل المطر الليلي على الفناء الأمامي ليشهد على الانفصال في العالم ♪
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
I swear
أقسم
I will never keep anything from you again.
لن أخفي عنك أي شيء مرة أخرى.
♪ We met again as strangers with our wonderful past ♪
♪ التقينا مرة أخرى كغرباء مع ماضينا الرائع ♪
What if it happens again?
ماذا لو حدث ذلك مرة أخرى؟
♪ A sharp arrow pierced our memories ♪
♪ سهم حاد اخترق ذكرياتنا ♪
Then may I die a terrible death.
ثم أتمنى أن أموت موتة فظيعة.
You shouldn't swear like that.
لا ينبغي لك أن تقسم بهذه الطريقة.
♪ Our longing is spreading like ink ♪
♪ شوقنا ينتشر مثل الحبر ♪
In other words.
بعبارة أخرى.
♪ The curtain separated love from hatred ♪
♪ الستار يفصل الحب عن الكراهية ♪
If I ever do it again,
إذا فعلت ذلك مرة أخرى،
may I never see you again.
لا أتمنى رؤيتك مرة أخرى.
♪ After going through endless sorrow, I can't let go of our love ♪
♪ بعد أن مررت بحزن لا نهاية له، لا أستطيع التخلي عن حبنا ♪
Five,
خمسة،
remember this oath you've just made.
تذكر هذا القسم الذي قطعته للتو.
♪ The past is like a sad dream ♪
♪الماضي مثل حلم حزين ♪
♪ Fully enjoying it can bring us happiness ♪
♪ الاستمتاع الكامل به يمكن أن يجلب لنا السعادة ♪
♪ That year, the pear blossoms were filled with laughter ♪
♪ في ذلك العام، كانت أزهار الكمثرى مليئة بالضحك ♪
♪ A night of snowflakes falling in disarray ♪
♪ ليلة من رقاقات الثلج تتساقط في حالة من الفوضى ♪
♪ All the perfection in the world hides deep regrets ♪
♪ كل الكمال في العالم يخفي ندمًا عميقًا ♪
♪ The blood in my heart is the spell of love ♪
♪ الدم في قلبي هو تعويذة الحب ♪
♪ I'll never miss you again in my dream ♪
♪ لن أفتقدك مرة أخرى في حلمي ♪
♪ When everything turns into smoke, I hope we can stay peaceful forever ♪
♪ عندما يتحول كل شيء إلى دخان، أتمنى أن نتمكن من البقاء بسلام إلى الأبد ♪
Did everything go well today?
هل كل شيء سار بشكل جيد اليوم؟
Then congratulations, Your Majesty.
ثم ألف مبروك يا جلالة الملك.
Rise, my beloved consort.
انهضي يا زوجتي الحبيبة.
Who's your beloved consort?
من هو زوجك الحبيب؟
Not consort,
ليس زوجا
but Empress.
ولكن الإمبراطورة.
My only wife.
زوجتي الوحيدة.
I never agreed to be your Empress.
لم أوافق أبدًا على أن أكون إمبراطورتك.
If you are unwilling,
إذا كنت غير راغب،
then I'll have to force you.
إذن سأضطر إلى إجبارك.
I'm wicked by nature and jealous.
أنا شريرة بطبيعتي وغيور.
♪ That year, the pear blossoms were filled with laughter ♪
♪ في ذلك العام، كانت أزهار الكمثرى مليئة بالضحك ♪
Now that you've gotten involved with me,
الآن بعد أن انخرطت معي،
you're in big trouble.
أنت في مشكلة كبيرة.
♪ A night of snowflakes falling in disarray ♪
♪ ليلة من رقاقات الثلج تتساقط في حالة من الفوضى ♪
♪ All the perfection in the world hides deep regrets ♪
♪ كل الكمال في العالم يخفي ندمًا عميقًا ♪
♪ The blood in my heart is the spell of love ♪
♪ الدم في قلبي هو تعويذة الحب ♪
♪ I'll never miss you again in my dream ♪
♪ لن أفتقدك مرة أخرى في حلمي ♪
I'm willing.
انا راغب.
♪ When everything turns into smoke, I hope we can stay peaceful forever ♪
♪ عندما يتحول كل شيء إلى دخان، أتمنى أن نتمكن من البقاء بسلام إلى الأبد ♪
Come on, take it slow.
هيا، خذ الأمر ببطء.
Align this properly.
قم بمحاذاة هذا بشكل صحيح.
Yes.
نعم.
Just put it there.
فقط ضعه هناك.
Is this silk straight?
هل هذا الحرير مستقيم؟
Make sure the happiness character isn't crooked.
تأكد من أن شخصية السعادة ليست ملتوية.
[Happiness]
[سعادة]
Let me tell you all,
دعوني أخبركم بكل شيء،
today
اليوم
is His Majesty's coronation day,
هو يوم تتويج جلالته،
and also His Majesty's
وأيضا جلالته
wedding day.
يوم الزفاف.
We cannot afford any mistakes.
لا يمكننا أن نتحمل أي أخطاء.
Yes.
نعم.
With Heaven as our witness,
مع السماء شاهدًا لنا،
and Earth as our support,
والأرض هي دعمنا،
we now share the ceremonial wine,
نحن الآن نتقاسم النبيذ الاحتفالي،
[Taiji Hall]
[قاعة تايجي]
forever binding our hearts.
ربط قلوبنا إلى الأبد.
Through all reincarnations, our love remains unshaken,
من خلال كل التناسخات، يبقى حبنا ثابتًا،
as steadfast as the mountains and seas.
صامدة كالجبال والبحار.
♪ The world would say ♪
♪ العالم سيقول ♪
♪ Romance cannot bear the clamor of splendor ♪
♪ الرومانسية لا تستطيع تحمل ضجيج الروعة ♪
♪ Her graceful shadow sways ♪
♪ ظلها الرشيق يتأرجح ♪
♪ New favors and old grudges hard to dispel ♪
♪ من الصعب التخلص من الامتيازات الجديدة والأحقاد القديمة ♪
The auspicious time has arrived.
لقد حان الوقت الميمون.
The royal wedding ceremony now begins!
الآن يبدأ حفل الزفاف الملكي!
♪ How many things are now left behind? ♪
♪ كم عدد الأشياء التي تركتها وراءك الآن؟ ♪
Long live the Emperor!
عاش الإمبراطور!
♪ Turning through time into a ballad ♪
♪ التحول عبر الزمن إلى قصيدة غنائية ♪
Long live the Empress!
تحيا الإمبراطورة!
♪ I heard the legends rise like the wind ♪
♪ سمعت الأساطير ترتفع مثل الريح ♪
♪ Only to fall back into nothingness ♪
♪ فقط للسقوط مرة أخرى في العدم ♪
♪ I dare not disturb the toll of the bell ♪
♪ لا أجرؤ على إزعاج قرع الجرس ♪
♪ Nor dare I awaken the dream ♪
♪ ولا أجرؤ على إيقاظ الحلم ♪
♪ Fearing the retelling ♪
♪ خوفا من إعادة السرد ♪
♪ Could never capture that breathtaking glance back then ♪
♪ لم أستطع أبدًا التقاط تلك النظرة المذهلة في ذلك الوقت ♪
♪ Loving you was devotion beneath moon and breeze ♪
♪ حبك كان إخلاصًا تحت القمر والنسيم ♪
The envoys from all states present their gifts!
المبعوثون من كافة الدول يقدمون هداياهم!
♪ Both ordinary love and hate ♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العاديين ♪
♪ Thus the era was shaken ♪
♪ وهكذا اهتز العصر ♪
♪ In youthful years of innocence ♪
♪ في سنوات الشباب من البراءة ♪
♪ When meetings would not come again ♪
♪ عندما لا تعود الاجتماعات مرة أخرى ♪
♪ The mortal realm was bound to start yet never end ♪
♪ كان من المفترض أن يبدأ عالم البشر ولكن لن ينتهي أبدًا ♪
The Nanyang envoy respectfully presents:
يقدم مبعوث نانيانغ بكل احترام:
a strand of azure jade jewels,
خيط من جواهر اليشم اللازوردي،
a golden phoenix hairpin with pearl adornments,
دبوس شعر على شكل طائر الفينيق الذهبي مزين باللؤلؤ،
and a pair of twin lotus jade bracelets.
وزوج من أساور اليشم اللوتس التوأم.
May Your Majesties...
جلالتكم...
Yingying,
ينغ ينغ،
today is the happiest day
اليوم هو أسعد يوم
of my entire life.
من حياتي كلها.
♪ I heard that in the spring of '64 ♪
♪ سمعت ذلك في ربيع عام 1964 ♪
Is it because you've finally become Emperor?
هل هذا لأنك أصبحت الإمبراطور أخيراً؟
♪ The wind rose at the mountain gate ♪
♪ ارتفعت الريح عند بوابة الجبل ♪
It's because I can finally
هذا لأنني أستطيع أخيرا
♪ Strange tales unfold in a book ♪
♪ حكايات غريبة تتكشف في كتاب ♪
♪ Recording their story ♪
♪ تسجيل قصتهم ♪
be with you forever.
سيكون معك إلى الأبد.
♪ Ridiculous words ♪
♪ كلمات سخيفة ♪
♪ Hastily blaming the cruelty of time ♪
♪ إلقاء اللوم على قسوة الزمن على عجل ♪
Then I wish Your Majesty
ثم أتمنى لجلالتك
to become a wise ruler in the future,
ليصبح حاكمًا حكيمًا في المستقبل،
bringing peace to Daning and prosperity to all lands.
جلب السلام إلى دانينج والرخاء إلى جميع الأراضي.
♪ Yet it still knocks on my heart and soul ♪
♪ ومع ذلك لا يزال يطرق على قلبي وروحى ♪
♪ Like a dream from another life ♪
♪ مثل حلم من حياة أخرى ♪
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
♪ Reincarnating in words ♪
♪ التناسخ في الكلمات ♪
I will always stay by your side,
سأبقى دائما بجانبك
never to be parted.
لا يمكن أن تنفصل أبدًا.
♪ Afraid others won't understand ♪
♪ خائف من أن الآخرين لن يفهموا ♪
♪ Afraid of stirring emotions for no reason ♪
♪ خائف من إثارة المشاعر بدون سبب ♪
♪ Better to have a beginning with no end ♪
♪ من الأفضل أن تكون البداية بلا نهاية ♪
In this life,
في هذه الحياة،
my family didn't meet a tragic end,
لم تلقى عائلتي نهاية مأساوية،
and Jun Che didn't become a tyrant.
ولم يصبح جون تشي طاغية.
It seems fate
يبدو أن القدر
has truly been changed by me.
لقد تغيرت حقا بالنسبة لي.
The envoy from Yue State presents gifts.
المبعوث من ولاية يوي يقدم الهدايا.
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟